<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>For Loops on Mr. Park's Site | mrparkonline</title><link>http://mrparkonline.github.io/courses/for/</link><description>Recent content in For Loops on Mr. Park's Site | mrparkonline</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 14:27:32 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://mrparkonline.github.io/courses/for/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction to For Loops</title><link>http://mrparkonline.github.io/courses/for/01forloop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mrparkonline.github.io/courses/for/01forloop/</guid><description>Sequence-based Iteration: For Loop For Loop Much like how a while loop will repeat its own block of code, For Loop will also repeat its own block of code.
For loops don&amp;rsquo;t depend on a conditional statement being True. For loops will repeat a finite amount of time dependent on the size/length of the iterating sequence.
# For Loop Format for __iterating_variable__ in __iterating__sequence__: your code here # end of for loop A for loop is started by using the keyword: for __iterating_variable__ is a label that you create to represent the individual items in the sequence No matter the iterating variable, the code within the for loop will execute The code within the for loop executes repeatedly until the iterating variable runs out of items to represent from the sequence What is a Sequence?</description></item><item><title>Integer Based Sequences With For Loops</title><link>http://mrparkonline.github.io/courses/for/02integerbasedsequences/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mrparkonline.github.io/courses/for/02integerbasedsequences/</guid><description>Integer Based Sequences w/ For Loops With studying Computer Science, we can use a lot of integers. By using range() function along with a for loop, we can start to analyze integer based sequences.
range() function The range() function can take 3 different arguments and it must have atleast 1 argument.
The range() function is a function that generates an iterable sequence of integers in an arithmetic progression.
IMPORTANT NOTE: the result of a range() function is not printable by itself.</description></item><item><title>Using For loops with Strings and Lists</title><link>http://mrparkonline.github.io/courses/for/03forloopwithstringsandlists/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mrparkonline.github.io/courses/for/03forloopwithstringsandlists/</guid><description>For Loop with Strings and Lists Index based iteration with Strings and Lists Both strings and lists are indexable, so we can access individual items by indicitaing an index with square brackets.
Examples:
print(&amp;#39;Hello&amp;#39;[1]) # Should output letter &amp;#39;e&amp;#39; at index of 1 e print([&amp;#39;Apple&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;Bananas&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;Kiwi&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;Strawberry&amp;#39;][2]) # Kiwi! Kiwi Let&amp;rsquo;s see some examples with for loops
# Using a for loop on a string with index # NOTE: programmers often use single letters when creating an iterating variable # I like to use i as &amp;#34;index&amp;#34; phrase = &amp;#39;Hello, World!</description></item><item><title>More Iterable Functions with For Loops</title><link>http://mrparkonline.github.io/courses/for/04iterablefunctionswithforloop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://mrparkonline.github.io/courses/for/04iterablefunctionswithforloop/</guid><description>Iterable Functions with For Loop We will be exploring more functions similar to range() where they also return an iterable sequence that we can iterate through with a for loop
1. sorted() function The sorted() function will return a sorted list in order from least to greatest from a sortable sequence.
For strings, they follow their ASCII table value order. For lists, it will depend on the datatype of each item.</description></item></channel></rss>